

Accomplished manager with 14 years of expertise in agile software engineering. Scales inclusive, collaborative teams through hiring and coaching. Drives the continuous improvement of people, processes, and products across teams with varying needs to deliver business value. Co-founded a non-profit to support local women in tech and enjoys speaking at conferences.

### **Experience**

# Senior Assistant Director of Software Engineering / Infotech Assistant Director of Development / Infotech

04/2020 - PRESENT 03/2018 - 04/2020

Manage day-to-day operations of a 3-person mobile development team and a 39-person web development team, scaling teams as needed. Drive successful on-time delivery of cloud-native Software as a Service (SaaS) products and over \$6M in annual enterprise software contracts.

- Expand web team 350% (11 to 39 developers), improving team capacity while maintaining an
  inclusive culture of collaboration across the division through hiring, onboarding, and coaching
- Define emerging tech strategy for the 300-person company in a 4-person committee
- Delivered a demo for a product expected to generate a new revenue stream; established business requirements with external partners and created a SaaS proof of concept that exceeded partner expectations; developed in a team of 2 using a serverless microservice architecture
- Plan long-term technical roadmaps and advocate with clients for upgrades over \$10k
- Won 1st place out of 7 teams judged on our business plan and pitch competition in fall 2018
   Empowering Women in Technology Startups (EWITS), a 10-week hands-on entrepreneurial training program at the University of Florida

**Co-Founder, Vice President / We Advance Tech Together, Inc.** 04/2019 – PRESENT Co-Founded 501(c)(3) non-profit to support local women in tech through community-building and mentoring.

- Cultivate meet-up growth to over 100 members through social media outreach and in-person events
- Public speaking at local meetups to international conferences, including the 2020 Virtual Grace
   Hopper Celebration with 39,000+ global attendees

#### Senior Lead Software Developer / Infotech Lead Software Developer / Infotech

04/2016 - 03/2018

12/2013 - 04/2016

Led development of web-based software suite through 5 annual release cycles, guiding feature squads from requirements gathering through release. Directed the 4-person tech debt team, prioritizing items to improve efficiency, reduce regression, and research technical upgrades.

- Reduced developer time to update models by 75%, saving 15 minutes of developer time per update
- 1st place of 13+ teams in 2017 and 2018 Infotech hackathons; in 2017, pitched the idea and formed a 7-person team to create a Google Docs add-on that saved over \$300k by automating behaviordriven design (BDD) document formatting
- Onboarded 6 developers, explaining processes, tools, and architecture of 3.5M+ lines of source code

### Senior Software Developer / Infotech Software Developer / Infotech Programmer/Analyst / Infotech

04/2012 - 12/2013 02/2010 - 04/2012 04/2006 - 02/2010

Implemented features in a self-managing agile team of 20+ developers, following agile team practices including test-driven development, pair programming, and continuous integration.

- Designed look-and-feel and built user experience of 7 new UI controls required to meet Section 508 accessibility guidelines
- Developed back-end business services to replace over 400k lines of code for a rewrite from layered monolith to service-oriented architecture

## **Open Source**

#### Member / .NET Foundation

05/2019 - PRESENT

Contributed to Microsoft Entity Framework 6.2.

- Improved start-up initialization performance by 85% (from 14 seconds to 2 seconds for a model with 600 tables)
- Submitted the pull request with no changes requested at code review; pull request title: Reduce start-up time by loading finished Code First models from a persistent cache

### **Technical Skills**

- Python, C#, JavaScript (jQuery, Vue.js)
- HTML, CSS, XML
- AWS: Aurora Serverless, CloudFormation, CodeBuild, CodePipeline, EC2, Lambda
- Traditional and Cloud-Native Architectures
- Test-driven development, CI/CD
- Agile methodologies: Lean, Scrum, XP

### **Education**

**B.S. Computer Engineering / University of Florida** 

**GRADUATED 12/2005**